Contact

www.linkedin.com/in/alilazim-510b156 (LinkedIn) github.com/alilazim (Personal) twitter.com/alilazim (Personal)

Top Skills
CTO
IT Manager
Projects Management

Ali Lazim

Founder/CEO at Medixbot

Old Bridge, New Jersey, United States

Summary

MSc. in Computer/Software/AI engineering with solid experience of more than 30 years in software engineering, Enterprise Security(MFA, Password Manager, PAM, Governance, etc.), MicroElectroMechanical Systems (MEMS), Cloud/OnPrem, project management and industry analysis.

Broad range of experience and demonstrated ability;

- Successfully combines deep technical and business/customer understanding.
- Deep, quick thinker; pragmatic solutions to thorny problems ondemand.
- Highly credible RE/DE Personnel skills with experiences in National, EU and International RE/DE projects.
- Wide experiences in the whole stages of the Software development life cycle.
- Extensive skills and experience in the whole processes of PMI project Management, Scrum and Agile.
- Communicates effectively across varied audiences.
- Instinctive understanding of the Open Source/Linux community dynamic.
- Extensive skills and experiences in electric electronic and mechatronic projects.

Deep technical understanding of "scale", "infrastructure", "high availability", and "security" issues. Thorough grasp of the subtleties of the software development process; pragmatic and successful ability to apply that understanding.

Specialties: IT, Software Development, Security, Penetration test, Auditing, IAM, Identity Governance and Projects Management: PMI Project Management, SCRUM and Agile, Microsoft Project.

Software Engineering and Development: Main Experiences in Open Source Languages and Tools; - Java Technologies, API's and

Frameworks (J2EE, J2SE, J2ME, Android), HTML5, Objective-C, Node.js, .Net, PHP.

Infrastructures/Technologies/Concepts: Cloud Computing, Google Cloud Platform (GCP), Amazon Web Services (AWS), Containers such as Kubernetes, BeyondCorp, P2P, GRID, Telecom & GSM infrastructure, Pattern Recognition, ANN, SOA, Web 2.0, RIA, JScript, Ajax, RSS, Web Push, VoIP Systems.

Hardware: Extensive skills and experiences in innovating, designing, developing, prototyping, managing and manufacturing; electric, electronic, mechanical and mechatronic products.

Experience

Work3 Teknoloji AS (Medixbot)
Founder/CTO
April 2019 - Present (4 years)
Vancouver, British Columbia, Canada

Founder and CTO of Biotechnology startup; Medixbot; Worldwide Distributed Virtual Hospital.

Fullstack Integrated Digital and Physical Healthcare Services illuminate, to simplify, to clarify.

https://www.medixbot.com

SAASPASS

Cofounder and Chief Technology Officer January 2012 - April 2019 (7 years 4 months)

San Francisco Bay Area

I started with SAASPASS from the start with coming up with the idea and researching how visible it is. I managed the whole stages of this product/ software development life cycle, DevOps, cloud/on-prem integrations and the live operations/maintenance.

In brief:

Windows, Mac OS X, Unix and Linux

System Architecture

On-prem integration and deployment

Cloud Computing, deployment and hosting (Google Cloud Platform (GCP),

Amazon Web Services (AWS))

Containers such as Kubernetes

Virtualization and VDI technologies

Agile/Scrum and PMP Project management

Databases design and development (SQL)

Software Analysis, Architecture and Technical research

Software Development and management in Java EE, Node.js,

React js, C++, Objective-C, .Net, PHP, Python

Aradiom

Chief Technology Officer September 2007 - December 2011 (4 years 4 months) Istanbul, Turkey

Leading the technical team of Aradiom which is the provider of many Mobile Applications in the field of finance and Governmental organizations.

Using and Applying the whole PMI management processes for the whole projects of Aradiom. Developing Software using the Agile methodologies.

CREA TECH

Co-founder / CEO and CTO
May 2004 - December 2010 (6 years 8 months)
Istanbul, Turkey

Play the Key role in starting Crea Technology which is the Turkcell Solution provider as well as the provider of many Mobile Applications which are accounted as the first to be done in Turkey and they are used by the biggest two Telsim VAS Providers. As well as managing the company as a CEO, play the role of CTO in leading the technical team in developing many Software's in different fields.

Using and Applying the whole PMI management processes for the whole projects of Crea.

Play the key role in innovation, designing and producing many electrical electronic and mechatronic products.

AO Neu Media GmbH Chief Technology Officer May 2002 - March 2004 (1 year 11 months) Ulm Area, Germany

Leading the technical team in AO for researching and developing the new technologies in the telecommunication sector and come up with new projects of VAS (SMS, EMS, MMS) platforms, applications, Java applications, games (J2ME) and IVR applications.

Aradiom

Co-founder and CTO

November 2001 - April 2002 (6 months)

Istanbul, Turkey

Play a Key role in starting Aradiom which is the Turkcell Solution provider as well as the provider of many Mobile Applications in the Turkish and international market. Works as an CTO leading the software development team in developing many Software's in the telecommunications field.

Sonera Zed

Web Project Leader

February 2001 - October 2001 (9 months)

Finland

Responsible for managing and developing the ZED web site (marketing and product pages including web interface of all pull and push VAS services). Also responsible for managing and developing web reporting tools and content management system.

Argesoft

Internet Project Leader

November 1999 - January 2001 (1 year 3 months)

Istanbul, Turkey

Leads, architects and develops many Internet, Intranet, E-commerce projects.

Dell

Software Developer and Architect

August 1998 - November 1999 (1 year 4 months)

Software architect and developer of the e-commerce, internet and intranet projects of Sentim (a distributor of the International company DELL).

ARGESOFT YAZILIM A.Ş.

Software Engineer

July 1997 - August 1998 (1 year 2 months)

Istanbul, Turkey

Part of the development team of the AgreLease software product (A project for the leasing companies).

Digitalica Ltd

3D Software Developer

August 1996 - June 1997 (11 months)

Istanbul, Turkey

The analysis and implementation of the Digitalica Editing, 3D effects and Still Image and Video Processing Solutions.

High Technical Institute Lecturer October 1995 - June 1996 (9 months) Libya

A lecturer in the Computer Engineering Department of the High Technical Institute in Libya: Software Engineering, Data Structures, Project Life Cycle and Management.

Al-Nahrain University (FKA; Saddam University) Assistant Lecturer October 1994 - July 1995 (10 months) Baghdad, Iraq

During my Master studies at Al-Nahrain University (FKA; Saddam University), I also worked as an Assistant Lecturer for one year.

Education

Al-Nahrain University

Master of Science (MSc.), Software Engineering · (1992 - 1995)

Al-Nahrain University
Bachelor of Science (BS), Software Engineering · (1988 - 1992)